AHMAD AGHAZADEH

Tabriz, Iran linkedin.com/in/ahmadaghazadeh github.com/ahmadaghazadeh

+98 (935) 218-5069 ahmad.aghazadeh.a@gmail.com stackoverflow.com/u/1770868

OVERVIEW

As a Senior Android and Full stack developer with over 10 years of professional experience. I focus on Android applications and their integration with the back end. Therefore, commitment to collaborative problem-solving, obeying Clean Code, Scrum, Clean Architecture, TDD, BDD, writing tests, and creating quality products is essential. I also train and guide staff and code review their code. I am skilled in Java, Kotlin, C#, and React. I work in an agile team and I constantly strive to learn new technologies to upgrade myself.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Android Developer

Jul 2022 - Present

Bulut Takin - Tabriz, Iran - Full Time

The Bulut Takin Company is a high-tech software company that develops startup, mid-size, and enterprise business products.

- Maintain communication with the UI/UX team on Figma to achieve an outstanding user experience
- Developed Shipping and Delivering application using Flutter framework run on Android POS terminal, with over 300 active users
- Implementing MVVM with a focus on SOLID, Modularization, Hilt, and Design Patterns, to increase development speed
- Successfully delivered 5 mobile applications and REST APIs and GRPCs to support 3 million requests monthly
- Trained 10+ individuals in handling software development cycles, as part of their induction processes

Full stack Developer Jul 2022 - Present

Bulut Takin - Tabriz, Iran - Full Time

- Using azure CI/CD Pipeline For publishing the Shipping and Delivering API
- Implementation of tracking and monitoring for the Shipping and Delivering application with Serilog, ELK
- Developed Shipping and Delivering API by using C#, ASP.Net Core, Blazor, SignalR, FluentValidation, MediatR, Redis, Scrutor, and CQRS
- Designed eventual consistency for Shipping and Delivering with communicate API with Sale API by using RabbitMQ, Redis, contract test, background service, and MassTransit
- Complete detailed programming and development tasks for React, JavaScript on the front-end and C# on the backend using DDD, TDD

Senior Android Developer

Jan 2011- Jul 2022

Shoniz - Tabriz, Iran - FullTime

Shoniz company produces high-quality chocolate and has comprehensive sales and distribution system. It also has an IT department that develops all applications needed, including real-time ordering, logistics, and accounting systems.

- Set up Firebase A/B testing on the Real-Time Ordering application and selecting the most effective mobile version, growing orders by over 5%
- Transform Market Research Application XML views and Gilde Respectively to Jetpack compose and Coli for easier support and enhancement
- Created automation tests(Mockito and Espresso), Decreasing the overall 24% of Google Crashlytics bug reports.
- Designed and launched Market Research Application using Kotlin with Koin, coroutines, LiveData, ViewModel, and Room
- Redesigned existing Real-Time Ordering Android Application and add Coroutine, LiveData, and Flow leading to better performance and fewer crashes
- Supervised a team of 3 developers to develop a Market Research Android Application with Clean Architecture, MVVM, and Kotlin, growing sales by about 10%

Full stack Developer Jan 2011- Jul 2022

Shoniz - Tabriz, Iran - Full Time

• Develop and maintain central identity service 4 and auth token-based authentication service, using Android Application and Web API

- Designed and launched Market Research application using EF core, C#, Rest, SQL server
- Successfully delivered 5 Web API and REST APIs and GRPCs to support 3 million requests monthly
- Refactored Real-Time Ordering API from dapper and store produce to Ef core for better integration
- Implementation of Real-Time Ordering web application by using MVC .net, JavaScript, Html, and CSS to create innovated dashboard for supervisor
- Supervised a team of 3 developers to develop a Market Research API with Clean Code, SOLID, and Unit Testing with growing sales by 10%

Android Developer Mar 2019 - Feb 2022

RPK Software Solutions - Toronto Area, Canada - Part Time

As a software company, RPK Software Solutions designs and develops web and mobile applications for Canadian organizations.

- Planned and published Learning Say Ken Language Android Application with 3 simples games using Kotlin, Retrofit, Room, Sqlite, MVVM, and Dagger for MVP(Minimum Viable Product) version
- Transform Learning Say Ken Language Android application XML views, Dagger, and Gilde Respectively to Jetpack Compose, Hilt, and Coli for more response to change
- Execute OAuth with Firebase authentication on Hunter Booking Admin Panel using React, Axios, Redux, and TypeScript
- Publish the Learning Say Ken Language Android app and alert product owners and testers via GitLab CI/CD, Fastlane, and Slack
- Developed Skani Language Learning Web Panel using React, Typescript, React, Axios, Redux

Android Developer 2011 - Jun 2019

Max Droid - Tabriz, Iran - Self Employee

As founder of Max Droid, I created and published numerous Android applications on Android Markets. The experience was enjoyable for me.

- Published over 20 applications using Java and Eclipse on Android Markets, earning over 25000 user reviews
- Developed an open-source Custom View CodeEditor project on GitHub, with 30+ forks and 180+ stars
- Published more than 10 games on Android Markets using Unity Engine and GameMaker
- Implemented the web-based payment method Like PayPal for applications, boosting items purchased at them
- Provided support to Android Market users and resolved problems quickly, earning more stars and reviews

SKILLS

Android, Java, Kotlin, MVVM, MVC, Coroutine, Jetpack Compose, Coli, Gilde, Retrofit, Koin, Dagger, Hilt, Room, Espresso, Mockito, JUnit, ViewModel, LiveData, Flow, A/B testing, Google Crashlytics, Serverless Architecture, Flutter, Bloc, Unity, Docker, SOLID, Clean Architecture, Agile, Scrum, GIT, CI/CD Pipeline, REST API, GRPC, integration tests, DDD, TDD, React, JavaScript, TypeScript, C#, .Net, Entity Framework, Dapper, ASP.NET Core, Dependency Injection, Scrutor, Redis, Serilog, ELK Stack, SignalR, AutoMapper, Background Service, HangFire, RabbitMQ, MassTransit, CQRS, Blazor, MediatR

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering(B.E.) in Software Engineering – University of Applied Science and Technology, Tabriz, Iran

Sep 2005 - Sep 2009

LANGUAGE SKILLS

English (C1) Persian (Native) Azerbaijani (Native)